# Rajesh Panicker

#### **Business Development**

Astute Technocrat having over two decades of in-depth ICT working experience and knowledge in areas of technical sales, partner management and business development. An assertive leader having resolve, clarity, integrity, magnanimity and openness to lead any team to achieve set objective and goals.



🔀 rajpan@hotmail.com

+91-9819858871

Triveni, 504, Mithchowkey, Marve Road, Malad (West), Bombay - 400 064, INDIA, Mumbai, India in linkedin.com/in/rajpan

## **SKILLS**

Key Account Management

Technology Sales

**Data Center Technologies** 

**Networking Technologies** 

**Cloud Computing** 

<u>Hybrid Cloud and Hyperconvergence</u>

Large Bid Management

**Enterprise Solution Sales** 

Partner Management

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# National Manager - Business Development

Connectivity Solutions &

09/2018 - Present

Connectivity Solutions is Cisco Gold Partner and Top SI in the BFSI, Manufacturing and Health Care Industry

Achievements/Tasks

- Hiring, mentoring a sales force to sell Networking solutions to the SME market across India
- Was instrumental in creating a customer value proposition and also architecting the solution offering called 'Secure Branch' using Cisco Meraki hardware + Meraki API and a set of other API to create a multitenant platform.
- Added 50 new customers Pan India.

#### Partner and CEO

#### Virtuoso Consultants

03/2014 - 08/2018

Virtuoso Consultants was into Solution Selling and Job Skilling

Achievements/Tasks

- Setup and running Skills India Short Term skill development center in Bangalore.
- Started a System Integration company to take on turnkey projects in areas of automation from the gate to the desk.
- Architected a solution called Gate2Desk for an integrated view of security infrastructure

## **Territory Business Manager**

Cisco Systems 🗷

05/2012 - 03/2014

Achievements/Tasks

- Awarded the Cisco Barbarian award in the Commercial Segment across APJC
- Successfully achievied quarter on quarter number through large partner management like IBM, Airtel, TCS etc...
- Running weekly, monthly, quarterly opportunity and funnel pipeline with partner organizations.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Strategic Consultant**

Commit Technologies 🗷

01/2010 - 04/2012

Commit Technologies is a Digital Marketing, Documentation company

Achievements/Tasks

- Took Commit a Technical Documentation Company from revenues of 2 crore to 5 crore.
- Go to Market Strategies for selling documentation services like Single Sourcing, E-Learning, and Instructional Design
- Won prestigious orders from Government and Defence companies for documentation service

# Senior Systems Consultant - BFSI and Large Enterprise Dell India

10/2008 - 12/2009

Achievements/Tasks

- Four quarters of number achievement of ~ \$1.2 Mn revenue per quarter.
- Helping account managers sell high-end servers and storage solutions.
- Selling Virtualization Services, Support Services, Managed Services etc.
- Customer presentation, proof of concept and product demonstrations for prospective customers.

## Country Manager - Sales, India

Kingston Technologies

05/2006 - 12/2007

Achievements/Tasks

- Holds the distinction of planning, developing and launching Kingston India sales department which included the creation of
  marketing plans, cost analysis, marketing and sales territories.
- Involved in building partnership with channel partner by training field sales on how to help channel partner make money in memory business bringing creditability to Kingston business and its sales force.
- Developed business from \$55M in 2006 to \$90M+ in 2007.
- Developed Flash business from under \$1Mn per month in 2006 to ~\$4.5Mn per month.
- Initiated independent service facility for Kingston, first of its kind from any memory vendor in India.

# Technical Marketing Manager, Platform Planning and Enablement APAC Intel Corporation

12/2000 - 05/2006

Achievements/Tasks

- Formulated plans for platform transitions for the APAC channel community.
- Efficiently worked with Channel Technical Managers, Country Sales Manager, Taiwan ODM Team and Reseller Product Group in US
  and top building block companies to deliver.
- Instrumental in implementing effective feedback process to ensure customer requirements are understood and implemented.
- Pivotal in launching dual core platform, transitioned processor series 5XX to 6XX and 8XX to mainstream product line, Q/Q (Q2-05/Q3-05) growth for these products stood at 150%.
- Significantly contributed in Bensley Server platform launch and ramp across APAC.

#### Past Experience

1992 - 2000

Achievements/Tasks

- Dec'94 Mar' 00 Oman Computer Services as Technical Consultant
- Feb'94 Dec'94 Dateline & Research Technologies (India) Ltd., as Network Engineer
- Feb'92 Jan'94 Zenith Computers (India) Ltd., as Senior Systems Executive

# **EDUCATION**

#### B'com

University of Mumbai